<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ocean Depths</string>
    <string name="close_popup_text">Tap to close</string>
    <string name="submarine_button_description">Submarine image button, tap to scroll to the top</string>
    <string name="blinking_text">Scroll down and dive!</string>
    <string name="main_title_description">How deep is the ocean?</string>
    <string name="main_button">Find out!</string>
    <string name="credits">App by Necromyd , 2023</string>
    <string name="sunlit_zone">The Sunlit Zone</string>
    <string name="sunlit_zone_text">The sunlit ocean zone, also known as the euphotic or epipelagic zone, is the uppermost layer of the ocean which sunlight penetrates and supports photosynthesis. This zone typically extends from the ocean surface down to a depth of around 200 meters. Within the euphotic zone, marine plants, such as phytoplankton, use sunlight to produce energy through photosynthesis, which forms the foundation of the ocean food chain. This zone is rich in biodiversity and is home to a wide variety of marine organisms, from small zooplankton to larger fish and marine mammals.</string>
    <string name="twilight_zone">The Twilight Zone</string>
    <string name="twilight_zone_text">The twilight zone, also referred to as the mesopelagic zone, is the ocean layer that begins from the edge of the euphotic zone (where sunlight diminishes). In this zone, sunlight is still present but extremely faint and appears as a dim twilight, hence the name. The twilight zone is characterized by a significant decrease in light intensity and a decrease in temperature with increasing depth. Many marine organisms in this zone have developed adaptations to low light conditions, including bioluminescence, the ability to produce their own light. Depending on the water clarity and the angle at which light penetrates, this zone tends to have a varying depth to which light may be seen in. Up to 1000m in the absolute best case scenario.</string>
    <string name="midnight_zone">The Midnight Zone</string>
    <string name="midnight_zone_text">The midnight zone, also known as the bathypelagic zone, is the oceanic layer that extends from the bottom of the twilight zone around 1000 meters deep. This zone is characterized by complete darkness, cold temperatures, and strong pressure. The midnight zone is one of the most mysterious and least explored regions of the ocean. Many of the organisms that inhabit this zone have developed unique adaptations to survive in the harsh conditions, such as pressure-resistant body structures and specialized feeding strategies.</string>
    <string name="abyssal_zone">The Abyssal Zone</string>
    <string name="abyssal_zone_text">The abyssal zone, often referred to as the abyssopelagic zone, is the deepest and most remote layer of the ocean. It begins at the edge of the midnight zone, around 4000 meters below the ocean\'s surface, and extends down to the ocean floor or 6000m. This zone is characterized by extremely high pressure, complete darkness, and near-freezing temperatures. The abyssal zone is home to a variety of unique and often bizarre organisms that have evolved to survive in these extreme conditions. It also contains hydrothermal vents, where superheated water rich in minerals emerges from the seafloor, supporting specialized ecosystems.</string>
    <string name="hadal_zone">The Hadal Zone</string>
    <string name="hadal_zone_text">The hadal zone is the oceanic zone that encompasses the deepest ocean trenches, ranging from around 6000 meters to the bottom of the ocean\'s deepest points. This zone is characterized by extreme pressure, complete darkness, and cold temperatures, similar to the abyssal zone. However, what sets the hadal zone apart is its unique geological features, including deep-sea trenches and subduction zones. Despite the challenging conditions, life has been discovered even in these depths, including specialized organisms that have adapted to thrive in the harsh environment.</string>
    <string name="coral_reef">Coral Reef</string>
    <string name="coral_reef_text">Coral reefs are vibrant underwater ecosystems formed by colonies of tiny animals called coral polyps. These incredible structures can be found in warm, clear oceans around the world, particularly in the Pacific and Indian Oceans. One fascinating fact about coral reefs is that they are often referred to as the "rainforests of the sea" due to their remarkable biodiversity, housing countless species of fish, marine plants, and other creatures. These reefs can thrive at varying depths, with some species able to grow in waters as shallow as one meter, while others can be found at depths up to 150 meters. They are not only essential for marine life but also play a crucial role in protecting coastlines from erosion and providing livelihoods for millions of people.</string>
    <string name="deepest_pool">World\'s Deepest Pool</string>
    <string name="deepest_pool_text">Deep Dive Dubai is a unique and state-of-the-art indoor diving facility located in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. It is known for its depth and special features. This facility holds the world record as the deepest indoor pool, with a maximum depth of 60 meters, attracting divers of all experience levels. With a simulated underwater city, controlled water temperature, and impressive lighting, it offers a unique diving experience and training for various diving techniques. In addition to diving, Deep Dive Dubai also offers entertainment and training programs.</string>
    <string name="eurotunnel">Eurotunnel</string>
    <string name="eurotunnel_text">The Eurotunnel, also known as the Channel Tunnel, is a remarkable engineering marvel connecting the United Kingdom and mainland Europe beneath the English Channel. Spanning approximately 35 kilometers (22 miles), it stands as one of the world\'s longest undersea tunnels. Notably, the Eurotunnel descends to depths of about 75 meters below the seabed and reaches a maximum depth of 115 meters below sea level at its lowest point. This impressive feat of infrastructure serves as a vital link for both rail and vehicle transportation, facilitating efficient travel and trade between the UK and continental Europe.</string>
    <string name="northern_fur_seal">Northern Fur Seal</string>
    <string name="northern_fur_seal_text">The northern fur seal, scientifically known as Callorhinus ursinus, is a captivating marine mammal primarily found in the North Pacific Ocean. These charismatic creatures are renowned for their luxurious, dark brown fur and distinctive external ear flaps. Northern fur seals are remarkable divers, capable of plunging to depths of up to 183 meters (600 feet) or more during their foraging expeditions. These remarkable diving abilities are essential for their survival, as they primarily feed on a diet consisting of various fish and squid species found in the cold, nutrient-rich waters of their habitat.</string>
</resources>